<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Отчёты | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/%D0%BE%D1%82%D1%87%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/%D0%BE%D1%82%D1%87%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Отчёты</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Отчёты</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/%D0%BE%D1%82%D1%87%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artificial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/%D0%B8%D1%81%D0%BA%D1%83%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B2%D0%B5%D0%BD%D0%BD%D1%8B%D0%B8-%D0%B8%D0%BD%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%BB%D0%B5%D0%BA%D1%82/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/%D0%B8%D1%81%D0%BA%D1%83%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B2%D0%B5%D0%BD%D0%BD%D1%8B%D0%B8-%D0%B8%D0%BD%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%BB%D0%B5%D0%BA%D1%82/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;libr&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Как дела?&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artificial intelligence&lt;/strong&gt; is computer programs and mechanisms capable of identifying problem situations, formulating tasks, finding solutions and making decisions based on certain criteria. This is an innovative technology that is currently developing at a rapid pace and is finding new applications in everyday life, economics, manufacturing, medicine and other fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;The development of artificial intelligence began in the middle of the XIX century, but the real heyday of this technology occurred in the XXI century. Today, AI is used in a large number of industries, contributes to the development of medical diagnostics, the transport and chemical industries, and robotics. Among the most famous AI applications are Siri, Google Assistant, Amazon Alexa – virtual assistants that help improve the convenience of human and computer communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;However, the development of AI is not without its problems. Among other things, there are questions about data security and human ethics. Some scientists and public figures call for caution regarding AI, fearing its power and possible social impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;It should be noted that there are several directions of AI development. These directions can be different and influence which type of AI to use for a specific task. One of the most interesting areas of development is the development of algorithms that will save resources and improve the quality of life of people around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;In order for artificial intelligence to become a real human assistant, scientists and specialists need joint interaction and discussion of this topic. On this path, it is important to consider all possible problems and risks for society. This is the only way to identify potential problems before they can be solved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reports</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/%D0%BE%D1%82%D1%87%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/%D0%BE%D1%82%D1%87%D0%B5%D1%82%D1%8B/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;libr&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Как дела?&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;reports&#34;&gt;Reports&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;##What is a report?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;A report is a document containing information about the work performed, the result of activities, events that have occurred or facts. It can be designed in various formats and applied in various fields, such as accounting, project management, medicine, scientific research, etc. The main purpose of the report is to convey information and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;##Why do I need a report?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;The report is needed to document and analyze information about activities or processes. It allows you to evaluate performance, determine success and problems in work, and make decisions based on the data obtained. Reports play an important role in organization, business, research, project management, etc. Depending on the goals and objectives, reports may have a different format and structure, but they are all aimed at providing information for decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;##Report content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The title page with the number of the laboratory work and the full name of the student.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formulation of the purpose of the work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Description of the results of the task:
– screenshots (screenshots) that record the performance of laboratory work;
– listings (source code) of programs (if any);
– program execution results (text or screenshot depending on
the task).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conclusions agreed with the purpose of the work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Answers to security questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;##Our reports&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;Our reports are executed in the Markdown system and necessarily contain screenshots of the work. Thanks to the markup language, their design becomes an easy task.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
